BRANDY CARDONA

ABOUT ME

IT professional with over 10 years of experience software testing, design, development, and maintenance; and almost 20 years of experience in various aspects of state government. Over 3 years of experience working remotely and using remote collaboration tools to effectively work with a remote team.

CHILD SUPPORT PROJECTS

NVKIDS, 2018 - PRESENT

Participated in Nevada Child Support Modernization project including requirement clarification sessions, joint technical and functional design sessions, conversion mapping, data model review, review of parallel testing results, interface design and user acceptance testing, implementation, management of phased rollout activities in legacy system, and post implementation activities.

RAPID, 2018

Assisted with design and implementation of State Collection and Disbursement Unit's new system, RAPID.

EIWO, 2017

Lead developer for design, development, and implementation of Electronic Income Withholding (eIWO) program for the State of Nevada.

WORK HISTORY

IT PROFESSIONAL, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, DIVISION OF WELFARE AND SUPPORTIVE SERVICES

October 2013 - Present

Develop, maintain, and design enhancements for mainframe and java applications used by the Child Support Enforcement Program. Including designing and updating database tables for enhancements. Review and analyze help desk tickets for issues reported by system users and participate in joint application design meetings.

BUSINESS PROCESS ANALYST, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, DIVISION OF WELFARE AND SUPORTIVE SERVICES

October 2012 – October 2013

Develop test plans which involve attending user requirement meetings and reviewing System Requirement Documents to identify functionality and potential problems for work items. Ensure systems are functioning as designed through the testing of all user requirements and creating and retesting defects. Execute batch processes that simulate time passage in non-production environments as required for testing purposes. Manage Bugzilla software and triage defects entered by staff.

IT TECHNICIAN, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND NATURAL RESOURCES, DIVISION OF WATER RESOURCES

October 2011 – October 2012

Manage work flows for creation and maintenance of water right data into the Division's existing datasets; maintenance of SQL data; assist staff and public with cartographic needs, querying of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) data, and post processing of field collection data; and develop training sessions for Division staff on the use of GIS software and data. Additional duties include assisting staff with technical report writing, and technical and statutory review of water right applications and application maps for publication.

WATER COMMISSIONER, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND NATURAL RESOURCES, DIVISION OF WATER RESOURCES

June 2007 - October 2011

Perform field work consisting of quarterly ground water level measurements in 9 basins, conduct annual ground water pumpage inventories in 3 basins, and complete field investigations as assigned. Prepare water usage reports for all 3 basins and assist staff engineers with completing other water usage reports as needed. GIS duties include assisting in the implementation of the division's water right mapping project, assist in development and maintenance of SDE geodatabase, creation of GIS data layers, and cartographic work for field assignments and staff as requested.

ASSISTANT TO STATE FORESTER FIREWARDEN, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND NATURAL RESOURCES, DIVISION OF FORESTRY

July 2005 - June 2007

Carried over IT and GIS tasks from Administrative Assistant position. Assisted the State Forester, Deputy State Forester, and Program Managers with administrative duties. Updated and revised policies and procedures manual. Reviewed and tracked legislative bills and prepared presentations and testimony for legislature. Assisted in the Biennial Budget preparation for the division and served as the State Office Liaison / Public Information Officer for the division.

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND NATURAL RESOURCES, DIVISION OF FORESTRY

December 2003 – July 2005

Performed all receptionist duties, handled fiscal and logistical components of the division's uniform contract, audited Conservation Camp monthly reports, and completed data entry and review for timesheets. Also assisted the division's IT Professional with implementing GIS projects, software and hardware installation and responding to user help desk requests.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX, 2011

Earned a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology with a concentration in Multimedia and Visual Communication. Program focuses on essential knowledge in core technologies such as systems analysis and design, database design, web technologies, and application development, implementation, and maintenance. The Multimedia and Visual Communication concentration emphasizes skills needed to facilitate internal and external communications, information content management, training, and marketing materials.

ASSOCIATE OF APPLIED SCIENCE IN GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS, WESTERN NEVADA COLLEGE, 2004

The GIS program at WNC covered core theories and competencies of spatial analysis, GIS databases, cartography, GIS trends and applications, and ArcGIS desktop and extensions. Completed internship and portfolio while working for the State of Nevada, Division of Forestry. Portfolio was based on analysis of the spread of Pinyon Ips in Western Nevada.

Page | 2 Brandy Cardona

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Eclipse
- Visual Studio
- Rational Application Developer
- Rational Business Developer
- Perforce Helix ALM
- Perforce Helix Core
- Bugzilla
- Toad for DB2
- GIMP
- WinSCP
- Java
- Enterprise Generation Language
- SQL/DB2
- HTML/CSS/Bootstrap
- Data Modeling

Page | 3 Brandy Cardona